# AMAN KUMAR PANDEY

## SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

https://github.com/Aman620-tech

(**in**) www.linkedin.com/in/aman-k-pandey

+91 9993935261



pandeyaman997@gmail.com

## PROFILE SUMMARY

I have 3.9 years of work experience as a Software Developer and 4 months of AWS Solution Architect interns, having Knowledge of ReactJs, AWS, Mysql, MongoDB, and Postgres. Mainly my work is to create a backend of an application according to the project's requirement, configure AWS services for the Deployment of the project, and store the data in S3, Project setup and I also have experience leading a team. Also, know Git and GitHub. Also, Know how to create a payment gateway like Stripe for our application. Done hosting through Heroku and Netlify, AWS.

#### TECHNICAL SKILL

FRONTEND: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript, Bootstrap, ReactJS.

BACKEND: NodeJS, Express.js, ORM (Sequelize, Mongoose), Stripe, Razorpay, stripe, TextServices,

Calling feature Implementation., etc

DATABASE ORACLE, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL,

**CLOUD** AWS (EC2, RDS, IAM, ELB, S3, VPC, AutoScaling, Route 53, lambda), GoogleCloud.

DevOps Tool: Git, GitHub, Docker. PROFESSIONAL SKILL

Leadership, Teamwork, Flexibility, Communication, Time Management

## EDUCATION

#### **BACHELOR's OF TECHNOLOGY**

Rajiv Gandhi Proudyogiki Vishwavidyalaya, Bhopal Computer Science and Engineering

#### **SENIOR HIGH SCHOOL**

Kamla Nehru Hr Sec School, Bhopal Physics, Chemistry and Maths

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# **Software Developer**

Jan 2023 - Present

BookAnArtist Melbourne, Australia

- Handling the third party API,
- and feature management.
- new feature build-up.
- · create the flow for the feature
- google feature and add it like login. merchant, etc.
- Configure S3 for image upload
- feature ownership, etc

#### **Software Developer**

July, 2022 - November 2022

**Brain Inventory** 

- Working as a full-stack with technologies Reactjs, Nodejs, MongoDB.
- Creating Account Software.
- Creating File sharing Application.
- Payment Gateways,
- AWS S3 setup
- Google login Implementation

## **Software Developer**

April, 2021 - June 2022

Micro Technologies India, Bhopal

- Backend developer.
- Configure S3 for image upload
- Project hosting through AWS EC2 and godaddy

#### **AWS Solution Architect Intern**

Dec 2020 - April, 2021

Micro Technologies India, Bhopal

- Provided Solutions for hosting WordPress website.
- Dynamic website hosting (ReactJS, NodeJS, and Mysql).
- Provided solutions for adding and giving access through IAM users.
- Hosting through S3 and Amplify ,etc.

Solutions Provided:-

- Provided Solutions for hosting static and dynamic websites.
- Setup an EC2 for the deployment of the project.
- Configuration of S3 Bucket.
- Created Identity and Access Management for accessing AWS services.

#### PROJECT

Micro-Com 2021

Full-Stack Developer

shopping center management. for local vendors

- Admin management
- shopkeeper Product management
- https://github.com/Aman620-tech/MicroComBusiness.git

Technology:- Nodejs, ReactJs, JavaScript, EC2, S3, MngoDB

Food-taste 2021

Full-Stack Developer

Project created for hotels/cafes to keep a record of the payment and bills of multiple hotels

- Admin management
- Hotel item management
- Order record

Technology:- Nodejs, ReactJs, JavaScript, Mysql

Hr-payroll 2022

**Backend Developer** 

This Project was created for the management of employees and their salaries

- Mail Information,
- User Management
- Transaction record
- Pdf creation of recorded data

Technology:- Nodejs, ReactJs, JavaScript, MongoDb

MyFitnessMantra 2022

**Backend Developer** 

This project was created for gym, trainer, user Management, Library Management

- User Management
- Razorpay integration
- Permission management
- https://myfitmantra.com/

Technology:- Nodets, Angular, TypeScript, MongoDb, S3, EC2

Numetric 2022

**Backend Developer** 

This Project Does the same work as a CA. It manages the account detail, keeps a record of the transactions, and helps to create a bill and a pay slip, It affects the user account.

- User Management
- Admin module handle
- API management
- https://numetric.work/

Technology:- NodeJs, JavaScript, MongoDb,Redis , S3, EC2

Book an Artist 2023-present

Software Developer

This Project Does the same work as a CA. It manages the account details, keeps a record of the transactions, and helps to create a bill and a pay slip, It affects the user account.

- https://bookanartist.co/
- buy now art flow and implementation
- Add gift card and apply in wallet, etc

Technology:- NodeJs, JavaScript, MySql, , S3, EC2, AWS lambda, etc

#### DECLARATION

I AMAN KUMAR PANDEY do hereby declare that the above-given information is true and correct to the best of my knowledge.